<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Feynman Diagrams</title><link>https://l-yc.github.io/physics-website/</link><description>Recent content on Feynman Diagrams</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://l-yc.github.io/physics-website/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://l-yc.github.io/physics-website/recap/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://l-yc.github.io/physics-website/recap/</guid><description>A Brief Recap of Fundamentals # Before we dive in, you will need to be familiar with basic particle physics and classical electrodynamics concepts. Here, we prepared a recap of these topics to refresh your memory (or lay out some essential fundamental concepts) before we move on into quantum electrodynamics and Feynman diagrams.
Subatomic Particles and Forces # The Standard Model # To explore quantum interactions, you should know have an awareness of our current understanding of the elementary particles that make up our universe.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://l-yc.github.io/physics-website/quantum-electrodynamics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://l-yc.github.io/physics-website/quantum-electrodynamics/</guid><description>Quantum electrodynamics # Combining the ideas of Quantum and Classical Electrodynamics, we have quantum electrodynamics. In essence, Quantum electrodynamics explains the phenomena of electric fields and magnetic fields in terms of the discrete interactions of charged particles and photons.
A word on momentum transfer # Newton&amp;rsquo;s 2nd Law states that force is the rate of change of momentum ($\vec p$), or $\vec F = \frac{d\vec p}{dt}$. Hence, for an object to exert a force on another, it must transfer momentum, given by $\vec p = m \vec v$.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://l-yc.github.io/physics-website/virtual-particles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://l-yc.github.io/physics-website/virtual-particles/</guid><description>Virtual Particles # Previously, we saw how the transfer of photons between electrons explains why they repel one another when close together.
But we still haven’t resolved the issue that conservation of energy seems to have been violated. How do we account for this?
Heisenberg Uncertainty Principle (HUP) # The Heisenberg Uncertainty Principle states that the more precisely the time of a particle is determined, the less precisely the energy can be determined.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://l-yc.github.io/physics-website/feynman-diagrams/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://l-yc.github.io/physics-website/feynman-diagrams/</guid><description>Feynman Diagrams # Now that we have laid out the fundamentals, let&amp;rsquo;s explore Feynman diagrams by diving right in!
What is in a Feynman Diagram? # Feynman diagrams may look like a huge jumbled mess of lines, but however complicated it may look, it only consists of lines and vertices (singular: vertex). Straight lines represent (observable) particles that are participating in the interaction, while squiggly lines represent virtual particles.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://l-yc.github.io/physics-website/applications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://l-yc.github.io/physics-website/applications/</guid><description>Applications of Feynman Diagrams # Significance of Feynman Diagrams # With its simplicity and elegance, the Feynman Diagram has been applied liberally in particle physics explanations. Using just a bunch of lines and squiggly lines, Feynman was able to explain and solve problems involving subatomic particle interactions easily. His diagrams are brilliant illustrations that allowed us to predict other particle interactions after constructing a single example.
But it hasn&amp;rsquo;t always been this way.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://l-yc.github.io/physics-website/try-it-yourself/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://l-yc.github.io/physics-website/try-it-yourself/</guid><description>Try It Yourself! # Here are some other interesting quantum phenomenea, try to draw the Feynman Diagram for each one of them!
Pair production # Did you know that particles can pop out of nowhere? Sometimes, the energy from photons can be converted to the formation of an electron and an positron, and this is known as pair production.
The equation of the interaction is: $$ \gamma \to e^- + e^+ $$ The $\gamma$ refers to photon, and it uses it&amp;rsquo;s energy to form an electron ($e^-$) and a positron ($e^+$).</description></item><item><title/><link>https://l-yc.github.io/physics-website/references/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://l-yc.github.io/physics-website/references/</guid><description>References # Hyperphysics. Applications of Feynman Diagrams. Retrieved from http://hyperphysics.phy-astr.gsu.edu/hbase/Particles/feyn.html
Hyperphysics. Quantum Electrodynamics. Retrieved from http://hyperphysics.phy-astr.gsu.edu/hbase/Forces/qed.html
Hyperphysics. Compton Scattering. Retrieved from http://hyperphysics.phy-astr.gsu.edu/hbase/quantum/comptint.html
Hyperphysics. Protons. Retrieved from http://hyperphysics.phy-astr.gsu.edu/hbase/Particles/proton.html
Hyperphysics. Elementary Particles. Retrieved from http://hyperphysics.phy-astr.gsu.edu/hbase/Particles/parcon.html
Hyperphysics. Fundamental Forces. Retrieved from http://hyperphysics.phy-astr.gsu.edu/hbase/Forces/funfor.html
Hyperphysics. Quarks. Retrieved from http://hyperphysics.phy-astr.gsu.edu/hbase/Particles/quark.html
Hyperphysics. Particle Interactions and Conservation Laws. Retrieved from http://hyperphysics.phy-astr.gsu.edu/hbase/Particles/parint.html</description></item></channel></rss>